Guide to the John Pintard Papers 1750-1925 (bulk 1770-1890) MS 490
New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Papers of the Servoss Family, 1806-1925
  - Subseries II: Financial and Business Records
    - Servoss Account Book, 1874 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Servoss Account Books, 1902-1913 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Servoss Account Books, 1915-1925 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1815-1860 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1815-1860 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1815-1860 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1860-1899 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1860-1899 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1860-1899 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Servoss Accounts, Bills, and Receipts, 1860-1899 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Subseries III: Legal Records
    The legal records of the Servoss family include documents relevant to their French spoliation claims, deeds for real estate, and other documents relevant to legal proceedings or filings.
    - Servoss Legal Records, 1806-1859 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Servoss Legal Records, 1860-1899 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Servoss Legal Records (Oversize), 1845 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Subseries IV: Notes and Ephemera
    The notes and ephemera are varied writings on many topics as well as fragmentary notes.
    - Servoss Handwritten Notes, 1826-1902 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Servoss Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Servoss Handwritten Notes, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Servoss Advertisements, Certificates, Circulars, 1828-1856 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Servoss Photographs and Drawings, 1865, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Servoss Newspaper Clippings, circa 1810-1890 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Series III: Papers of Other Family and Associates, 1750-1915
  The Papers of Other Family and Associates contain the correspondence, financial and business records, legal records, and genealogies of individuals either related to or involved in the dealings of John Pintard.
  - Subseries I: Correspondence
    This subseries contains correspondence between individuals related to or known by John Pintard. It includes letters between his daughter Eliza and her husband Richard, as well as correspondence between business partners and friends of John Pintard.
    - Letters from Eliza Pintard Davidson to Richard Davidson, 1816 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letters to and from Associates and Family of John Pintard, 1758-1804 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Letters to and from Associates and Family of John Pintard, 1805-1820 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Letters to and from Associates and Family of John Pintard, 1821-1858 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Subseries II: Financial and Business Records
    This subseries contains financial and business records of friends and relatives of John Pintard, including his uncle Lewis Pintard.
    - Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1779-1813 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Subseries III: Legal Records
    This subseries contains financial, estate, and business records of friends and relatives of John Pintard, including leases, indentures, and wills.
    - Legal Records, 1766-1820 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Legal Records (Oversize), 1708, 1808 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Subseries IV: Notes and Ephemera
    The notes and ephemera includes fragmentary notes and varied writings on many topics such as Native Americans, abolition, New Orleans, etc.
    - Notes and Ephemera, 1750-1770 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Notes and Ephemera, circa 1850-1915 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Subseries V: Genealogies
    The Genealogies subseries contains family trees and other documents tracing the Pintard family line.
    - Genealogies, 1783-1915 (Box 13, Folder 9)